The new morning we've finally found
やっと見つけた　新しい朝は
Yatto mitsuketa atarashii asa wa
is being hampered by the past.
月日が邪魔をする
Tsukihi ga jama wo suru
What we chased after wasn't the future,
向かう先は　「次」じゃなくて
Mukau saki wa tsugi ja nakute
but the past so full of remorse.
「過」ばかり追いかけた
Sugi bakari oikaketa
The ruthless memories won't stop playing;
鳴り止まない　容赦ない思い出たちは
Nariyamanai yousha nai omoide tachi wa
they won't be forgiving us for a long time.
許してくれそうにもない
Yurushite kuresou nimonai
It's about now that a teardrop
そろそろかな　手探り　疲れた頬を
Sorosoro kana tesaguri tsukareta hoho wo
beings to roll down my fatigued cheeks.
葛藤がこぼれ落ちる
Kattou ga koboreochiru
Will this rain ever stop?
雨は　いつか止むのでしょうか
Ame wa itsuka yamunodeshouka
I've been freezing for a long time.
ずいぶん長い間　冷たい
Zuibun nagai aida tsumetai
Why does the rain continue to fix on me?
雨は　どうして僕を選ぶの
Ame wa doushite boku wo erabuno
I wonder if it could embrace me.
包まれて　いいかな
Tsutsumarete iikana
Today, the rain falls again;
雨は　止むことを知らずに
Ame wa yamu koto wo shirazuni
endlessly it falls knowing no end.
今日も降り続くけれど
Kyou mo furitsuzukukeredo
We nestle close to each other to share the warmth
そっと　差し出した傘の中で
Sotto sashidashita kasa no naka de
under this umbrella, you gently held out to me.
温もりに　寄り添いながら
Nukumori ni yorisoinagara
Colonel...
大佐…
There's no need... for you to perform human transmutation.
人体錬成なんて…
する必要は…ありません
You'll do it, won't you, Mustang?
するでしょ　マスタング君
Now!
さあ
I will.
分かった
Oh, so you'll do it?!
やってくれるかね
I'll do as you say, Lieutenant.
分かったよ　中尉
I will not perform human transmutation!
私は人体錬成はしない
You're going to abandon her? That's not very nice of you.
見捨てるの　冷たいねぇ
Abandon?
見捨てる
That's the last word I want to hear from someone who uses these guys as pawns.
この者たちを捨て駒のように扱う
貴様に言われたくないな
I'm sure they're happy to be my pawns.
捨て駒でも彼らは幸せだろうよ
They were abandoned by their parents and would have died long ago if it hadn't been for me.
親に捨てられ　そのままでは
死んでいたであろう者たちに
Yet, I gave them food and the highest education possible.
食事を与えた
一流の教育を与えた
I also gave them the meaning to live.
そして　存在意義を与えた
They're thankful.
この者らは私に感謝しているさ
And this is precisely why you get tripped up by your enemy.
そんなことだから
貴様は足元をすくわれるのだ
What are you-
何を…
He disappeared?
消えた
Well, I'm  thankful at least.
感謝してるぜ
I was able to capture you thanks to your stupidity.
こうやって てめぇを捕まえられるんだからな
L-Let go!
は…放せ
Hurry up and let everyone go!
さっさとみんなを解放しろ
Or else...!
さもないと…
I-I'm the only doctor here who can use alchemy!
い…今…
この場で錬金術を使える医者は
私だけだ
If you kill me, that woman is as good as dead!
私を殺せばあの女は助からんぞ
Don't you get it?!
分かっているのか
You're sounding pretty darn lame right now, Mister Doctor.
セリフが三流だぜ　お医者様よう
A philosopher's stone...
賢者の石…
Get the fuck out of my way!
邪魔だ
Lieutenant!
中尉　しっかりしろ
Hang in there!
Lieutenant! Open your eyes!
中尉　目を開けろ
Lieutenant...
中尉　中尉　中尉
Lieutenant...!
Lieutenant!
You all right?!
大丈夫か
If I can just reach that...
あれさえあれば…
死ぬな　中尉  しっかりしろ
Don't die!
Get yourself together, Lieutenant!
This is more important!
こっちが先です　ここは任せて
Leave this to me.
Lieutenant!
中尉
I've stopped the bleeding.
とりあえず出血は止めました
You need to let her see a doctor right away.
あとはちゃんとお医者様に
I'm in your debt. Thank you.
すまない　ありがとう
I'm sorry, Colonel...
大佐　すみません…
Don't speak. Just rest for now.
しゃべるな　休んでいろ
Thanks for understanding my glance.
私の目くばせに
よく気づいてくださいました
We've known each other for a while, after all.
つきあいが長いからな　それに
Furthermore, you were glaring at me as if you were trying to say,
人体錬成なんてしたら撃ち殺してやる
"I'll shoot you to death if you perform human transmutation."
ってな形相で　君がにらむのでね
That was the last of them, eh?
最後の１人か
Thanks, guys.
みんな　すまない　助かった
You saved us.
なに　いいってことよ
Don't worry about it, man.
Right! The philosopher's stone!
そうだ　賢者の石
King Bradley.
キング·ブラッドレイ
His wounds aren't healing...?
傷口が再生してない…
Long time no see, Mustang.
久しぶりだな　マスタング君
It certainly has been a while.
お久しぶりです
You look awfully different from how I remember.
以前とお変わりないご様子…
とは言い難いお姿ですね
Bradley, eat this!
ブラッドレイ　くらえ
I was certain you'd attempt human transmutation...
君なら
目の前で大切な者が倒れたら
if someone precious were to fall right in front of your eyes.
迷いなく人体錬成に走ると思ったのだがね
You're right, I probably would have back then.
少し前の私なら
そうだったかもしれません
But now, I have people by my side who are willing to stop me and point me toward the right path.
しかし
今の私には止めてくれる者や
正しい道を示してくれる者がいます
When you start thinking that humans are pitiful creatures that never learn,
いつまでも学ぶことを知らん
哀れな生き物かと思えば
there are those like you who knock us off our feet by learning and evolving at such a quick pace.
君たちのように短期間で学び
変化する者もいる
Humans are just...
まったく人間というやつは…
...so unpredictable, it infuriates me.
思いどおりにならなくて腹が立つ
What's the matter?
どうした
He's right underneath...
この下に…
Deep below.
真下の深い所にいます
Damn you!
この
I won't allow you to get in his way!
あのお方の邪魔はさせん
Give it up, old man.
あきらめな　じいさん
お前はこのオレが…
You're already-
Jerso!
ジェルソ
Pull yourself together!
しっかりしろ
G-Get yourselves out of here...!
に…逃げろ…
Shit.
やばい
Something truly fearsome is approaching.
来ます　恐ろしい何かが
Look after the lieutenant for me.
すまん　中尉を頼む
Colonel!
大佐
A-Attaboy, Bradley.
よ…よくやった　ブラッドレイ
I sure am skilled at raising-
さすが私が育てた…
Colonel Mustang, you're the fifth sacrifice.
マスタング大佐　君が５人目
The fifth and last.
最後の１人だ
Again?
まただよ
Why the heck is it so rowdy today?
今日はなんだってこんなに騒がしいんだ
Ah, the solar eclipse has begun.
日食が始まったのか
この手はあまり
I didn't really want to have to use this method,
使いたくなかったのですが
but we're fairly short on time right now.
しかたありません
時間がないのです
We're going to force you to open the gate, Colonel Mustang.
強制的に扉を開けさせてもらうよ
マスタング大佐
人体錬成など…
I certainly won't perform-
君にその気がなくてもかまわん
It doesn't matter whether you're willing to or not.
人体錬成の知識を持った錬金術師が
An alchemist possessing the knowledge of human transmutation was assimilated by Pride.
プライドと同化済みだ
He has the construction formula.
構築式は彼が持っている
固定しました
I've secured him.
どいていなさい　ラース
Step aside, Wrath.
さて　君はどこを持っていかれるのかな
Well, I'm curious as to what they're going to take from you.
大佐
Colonel!
ダメです　巻き込まれます
No! You'll be dragged into it!
大佐
Colonel!!
人体錬成はなされた
The transmutation is complete.
さっきの眼鏡じじいか
That's the four-eyed geezer?
Where is the Colonel?
大佐は
Worry not.
安心したまえ
今ごろマスタング君は父上のところだ
He should be with our father by now.
Though I certainly can't guarantee that he is with no physical defects.
五体満足かどうかは保障しないがね
さて  私はご覧の有様なわけだが…
As you can see, I'm fatally wounded.
アメストリス大総統を討ち取って
Who shall be the one to win fame for defeating the Führer President of Amestris?
名を上げるのは誰かね
Will it be a chimera?
合成獣か　よそ者か
A foreigner?
Mustang's pet?
マスタングの犬か　それとも
Or perhaps, will all of you band together to take me down?
全員でかかってくるか
なんだ　これ…
What the hell...?
ボロボロのおっさん一人に
Why do I get the feeling we won't stand a chance against one wounded old man?
勝てる気がしねぇ
真下…あの穴の下
Underneath...
Right beneath that hole.
メイが真下にいるって言った途端
The four-eyed geezer went nuts as soon as May said there's someone underneath that place.
眼鏡じじいがうろたえた
あのお方の邪魔はさせんってよ
Said something about not letting us get in his way.
どうやら　この下には
Seems like they don't want us going further underground.
行ってほしくないみたいだぜ
あれが中心か
So that must be the center.
そうです
That's right.
真下にすごい気の塊があります
I feel a huge cluster of energy right below us.
ならば…
If that's the case...
大佐
Colonel!
５人目です　父上
He's the fifth sacrifice, father.
I'd like to say that we've gathered all five,
Are you all right, Colonel?!
５人そろった…
Colonel!
と言いたいところだが
Get yourself together, Colonel!
アルフォンス·エルリックが
but Alphonse Elric has yet to come over to this side.
こちらに来ていない
大丈夫かよ　大佐
Are you okay, Colonel?!
鋼のか…
Fullmetal...?
どこだ　ここは
Where the hell are we?
親玉のところだよ
We're with the big cheese now.
大佐　一体何があったんだ
What in the world happened, Colonel?
真っ白い空間の
I was thrown in front of a large gate in some white room...
大きな扉の前にほうり出されて…
扉　まさか
Gate?!
Don't tell me they took something from you?!
どっか持ってかれたんじゃ…
いや　手も　足も…
But you still have all your limbs...
鋼の  この暗闇の中で
I'm surprised you can see me when it's so pitch-dark out here, Fullmetal.
よく私の姿が分かるな
What are you talking-
何言って…
真っ暗で　何も見えん
It's too dark for me to see anything.
明かりは　明かりはどこだ
The light.
Where's the light?
まっ　まさか…
I-It couldn't be...
目が見えないのですか
So you've lost your vision.
How convenient.
それはいい
正直　今の国家錬金術師の中では
Truth be told, you have the most troublesome ability out of all the state alchemists,
あなたの能力がいちばん厄介ですから
so I'd much rather you sit there and weep.
そこで　打ちひしがれていなさい
大佐…
Colonel...
人体錬成　やっちまったのかよ…
You performed human transmutation...?
鋼の
Fullmetal.
私がそんなことをすると思うか
Do you really think I'd do something like that?
強制的に
We forcefully had him open the gate.
扉を開けさせてもらいました
結果オーライというやつですね
But the result is all that matters.
Though Colonel Mustang would have been the most troublesome opponent,
これでいちばん厄介な
マスタング大佐の戦闘力は
ゼロに等しくなりました
with this, he's utterly useless in battle.
真理は残酷だ
Truth is cruel.
身の程をわきまえず死人をよみがえらせ
Out of the cocky ones who tried to revive the dead in order to be embraced by their mother's warmth again,
母のぬくもりを求めた者は
立ち上がるための足と
one of them was robbed of his leg with which to stand, and his one and only brother was also taken from him.
ただ一人の家族を持っていかれ
もう一人は体を丸ごと持っていかれ
The other was stripped of his entire body which left him unable to feel warmth at all.
ぬくもりを感じぬ姿に
亡くした子を求めれば
The woman who longed for her dead child was given a body no longer able to reproduce.
二度と子を与えられぬ体に
そして　国の先を見据えた者は
Now, the one who had his eyes fixed on the country's future was robbed of his vision;
視力を持っていかれ
その未来を見ることができなくなった
never again will he be able to see what the future holds.
人間が思い上がらぬよう
He gives humans their suitable forms of despair to prevent them from getting too conceited.
正しい絶望を与える
それこそが
He is the existence which you humans refer to as 'God'.
お前たち人間が神とも呼ぶ存在
真理だ
Truth.
How is that fair?!
納得いかねぇ
オレたちみたいに
Those of us who acted on our own initiative certainly deserved it.
自発的にやらかしたのは納得するさ
だが　する気のないヤツが
But someone who wasn't even willing was dragged into human transmutation, robbed of his vision,
無理やり人体錬成に巻き込まれて
視力を持ってかれて
and you say that's well-deserved?
それが正しいっていうのか
Truth is too illogical for me to accept!
そんな筋の通らねぇ真理は認めねぇ
父上の邪魔をするつもりか
Are you planning on getting in father's way?
貴様　本当の名はなんという
What is your true name?
名はない
I have no name.
捨てた
I've disposed of it.
What a coincidence.
それは奇遇だな
私も己の本当の名を知らん
I, too, do not know my real name.
名なし同士
A duel to the death between two nameless beings shall make quite a show.
殺し合うのもおもしろかろう
メイ
May!
いました
There he is.
How dare she open up a hole on the roof of my house...
私の家に穴を空けるとは
あの娘…
He looks different now, but judging from that aura...!
外見は変わってますが  その気配
不老不死の親玉さんですね
You're the immortal leader, aren't you?!
Sir Alphonse?!
アルフォンス様
どうしたんですか
What happened to you?!
分からない　目を覚まさないんだ
I don't know.
He just won't wake up.
そんな
No way!
アルフォンス様  アルフォンス様
Sir Alphonse! Sir Alphonse!
目を覚ましてください
Please, wake up!
アルフォンス様
Sir Alphonse!!
It's...
体…
僕の…体だ
It's... my body...
ずっと待ってた
I've been waiting for you.
おかえり
Welcome back.
なんだよ　この細い腕
What's with this thin arm?
I'm skin and bone.
骨と皮ばかりで
立っているのがやっとじゃないか
I'm barely able to stand.
こんな…
I...
There's...!
こんな体で戦えるわけない
There's no way I'll be able to fight with that body!
Everyone's giving their all!
みんな戦っているのに
僕と一つになるのがイヤなの
You don't want to reunite with me?
そんなわけないだろ
Of course I do!
ずっと　ずっと　ずっと
I've... I've always dreamed of getting my body back!
元の体に戻ることを考えてきた
それなのに…
But...
今はダメだ　そんな体じゃダメだ
Not now.
I won't be able to fight with that body!
Not with that body...
そんな体じゃダメなんだ…
あっちに戻りたい
Do you want to go back to the other side?
その体であっちに戻りたい
Would you like to go back with that body?
行くなら止めない
If so, I won't stop you.
ごめん　また来るから
Sorry.
I'll come again.
もう少し頑張ってて
Hang in there for a little longer!
必ず来るから
I'll definitely come again!
絶対　約束するから
I swear! It's a promise!
アル
Al!
You okay, Al?!
アル　大丈夫か
アルフォンス様
Sir Alphonse!
アル
Al!
Master.
師匠　兄さん　メイ
Brother.
May!
って　ここは…
Wait, where am-
仲間を助けるために
In order to help your friends,
you leave behind the body you've been longing after for years.
長年捜し続けた肉体を置いていく
気高い僕の魂よ
My soul, you are beyond dignified.
君の入れ物として誇りに思う
I am nothing but proud to be your container.
けど  君が戻ることで
But the fact that you went back may lead to the world being submerged in despair,
この世が絶望に満ちてしまう
かもしれないんだよ
アルフォンス
Alphonse.
５人　そろった
That...
...makes all five of you.
Ever since that day passed,
あの日からずっと
Ano hi kara zutto
I promised myself that I'd never cry.
泣かないと決めてきたけど
Nakanaito kimetekitakedo
But even while I hoarded up the pain,
痛みを重ねても
Itami wo kasanetemo
there was something I couldn't forgive myself for.
何かを許せずにいた
Nanika wo yurusezu ni ita
I'll never be able
もう戻れない
Mou modorenai
to return to those days.
いくつもの日々
Ikutsumo no hibi
I'm still powerless.
僕はまだ何もできずに
Boku wa mada nanimo dekizuni
I watch as the shards of memories disappear, one by one;
君のいた記憶の破片
Kimi no ita kioku no kakera
memories of when you were still with me.
またひとつ 消えてゆく
Mata hitotsu kieteyuku
I long to become
今日よりもっと
Kyou yori motto
stronger than I am now,
強くなりたい
Tsuyoku naritai
so that my voice will eventually reach you.
この声がいつか届くように
Kono koe ga itsuka todokuyouni
If the wind happens to stop
歩き続けて
Arukitsuzukete
in the midst of my long journey,
風が止んだら
Kaze ga yandara
I'll look up at the sky in search of you.
君を探して空見上げるよ
Kimi wo sagashite sora miageruyo
Beyond the daybreak, a ray of light breaks free.
夜明けの先に光がさすよ
Yoake no saki ni hikari ga sasuyo
A rainbow spans across the sky.
虹がかかるよ
Niji ga kakaruyo
次回　鋼の錬金術師
日本語字幕仕上げ：FAYFAY
Courage is brought into submission by force,
Fullmetal  Alchemist
第６０話　『天の瞳、地の扉』
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
and happiness is shattered to pieces.
世界は　闇に包まれた
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 60, Eye of Heaven, Gateway of Earth.
The world became engulfed in darkness.